<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Purplicious Cupcakes]]></title>
  <link href="http://purplicious.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://purplicious.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-06-16T19:10:07-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://purplicious.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Robin]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pina Colada Cupcakes]]></title>
    <link href="http://purplicious.github.com/blog/2012/05/27/pina-colada-cupcakes/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-27T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://purplicious.github.com/blog/2012/05/27/pina-colada-cupcakes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div>Quantity: unknown. I used this recipe to make a big top cupcake, but lets just guess that it would have made around 22 small top cupcakes.

Cake Ingredients
<ul>
    <li>2 c flour</li>
    <li>1 t baking soda</li>
    <li>1 t baking powder</li>
    <li>½ t salt</li>
    <li>2 c shredded coconut</li>
    <li>2/3 c coconut oil</li>
    <li>½ c pineapple juice (from canned pineapple)</li>
    <li>1 ½ c sugar</li>
    <li>1 and 3/4 c coconut milk (1 can)</li>
    <li>1/4 c soymilk</li>
    <li>1 T vanilla extract</li>
    <li>1 T apple cider vinegar</li>
</ul>
Cake Directions

Melt oil in glass measuring cup in oven (or on stove using low heat if you don&#8217;t have a pyrex measuring cup). Add sugar, milks, vanilla, and pineapple juice to coconut oil and whisk to combine.

Sift together the first 4 dry ingredients in a large bowl. Add the coconut.

Add dry ingredients to wet, until incorporated. Add vinegar. Mix slightly and pour.

Bake in a 350º oven for 24 minutes.

Filling Ingredients
<ul>
    <li>1 can pineapple</li>
    <li>½ c sugar</li>
    <li>1/4 cup cornstarch</li>
    <li>1 c pineapple juice (dilute with water if there&#8217;s not enough)</li>
</ul>
Filling Directions

Stir together sugar, pineapple, and half of the juice in a saucepan over low heat. 

In separate bowl, using a whisk or an immersion blender, blend the remaining juice with the cornstarch, and then add to the saucepan. 

Cook over low heat, stirring occasionally, for 15 minutes or until very thick. Cool.

Icing Ingredients
<ul>
    <li>½ c earth balance coconut spread</li>
    <li>½ c palm shortening</li>
    <li>1 t vanilla</li>
    <li>½ cup coconut milk (use the part from the can that is thicker)</li>
    <li>4 c powdered sugar</li>
</ul>
Icing Directions

Beat together the earth balance, palm shortening, and coconut milk until fluffy.

Add the confectioner’s sugar, sifting it in, and then beat until smooth and fluffy (~3 minutes).

Add vanilla and beat for 3 more minutes.

</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Blueberry cupcake experiment]]></title>
    <link href="http://purplicious.github.com/blog/2012/04/30/blueberry-cupcake-experiment/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://purplicious.github.com/blog/2012/04/30/blueberry-cupcake-experiment</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Please excuse any <del>misinformation</del> lies in this posting, but these cupcakes were made, eaten, and discussed approximately 387465 days ago, and that in conjunction with having a memory equivalent of a snail&#8217;s, makes my rendition of this story almost guaranteed to be slightly different than real life.</p>

<p>Once upon a time, there was a super sweet, amazing girl named Amber. Amber was having a rough week, and therefore in need of some cheerful (but not too cheerful) cupcakes. That was how the &#8220;blueberry&#8221; cupcakes were born. I thought that blue cupcakes would be fitting since Amber had been feeling blue, and everyone (everyone = me) wants a cupcake to sympathize with them by matching their mood, right? So, what Eidelyn and I learned after presenting people with these chocolate cupcakes topped with blue vanilla icing, was that humans associate colors with flavors. And the flavor that our human friends associate with blue is blueberry. So, then we wondered if we let them think it was blueberry, would their mind control win in a battle against their taste buds, leading them to believe that the cupcakes were indeed blueberry, when they were only vanilla. Some people might think it was a mean trick to treat their friends like lab rats by performing social experiments on them, but everyone already knows that I&#8217;m mean, and Eidelyn will basically sacrifice all of her morals in the name of science. So, basically those people would be wrong. Yay science!</p>

<p><a href="http://ieatcupcakes.com/2012/04/30/blueberry-cupcake-experiment/img_1717/" rel="attachment wp-att-1100"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-1100" title="&quot;blueberry&quot; cupcakes" src="http://ieatcupcakes.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/04/IMG_1717-510x382.jpg" alt="&quot;blueberry&quot; cupcakes" width="510" height="382" /></a></p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>

<p><a href="http://ieatcupcakes.com/2012/04/30/blueberry-cupcake-experiment/img_1719/" rel="attachment wp-att-1101"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-1101" title="&quot;blueberry&quot; cupcakes" src="http://ieatcupcakes.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/04/IMG_1719-510x382.jpg" alt="&quot;blueberry&quot; cupcakes" width="510" height="382" /></a></p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>

<p>This is what cupcakes look like when they get tucked into bed for the night.</p>

<p><a href="http://ieatcupcakes.com/2012/04/30/blueberry-cupcake-experiment/img_1720/" rel="attachment wp-att-1102"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-1102" title="Tucked into bed" src="http://ieatcupcakes.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/04/IMG_1720-510x382.jpg" alt="Tucked into bed" width="510" height="382" /></a></p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>

<p>This little cupcake house is care of Emily, my favoritest baker ever! My cupcakes have never been so excited to go for a ride in the car before! They really liked looking out the windows.</p>

<p><a href="http://ieatcupcakes.com/2012/04/30/blueberry-cupcake-experiment/img_1722/" rel="attachment wp-att-1103"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-1103" title="Cupcake house" src="http://ieatcupcakes.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/04/IMG_1722-510x382.jpg" alt="Cupcake house" width="510" height="382" /></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cafe Flore Strawberry shortcake cupcake]]></title>
    <link href="http://purplicious.github.com/blog/2012/03/11/cafe-flore-strawberry-shortcake-cupcake/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-11T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://purplicious.github.com/blog/2012/03/11/cafe-flore-strawberry-shortcake-cupcake</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After accepting an invitation to vegan brunch from Shane, Jessica and I had a planning session for our next LA road trip over a raw cacao (cacao!) shake and a tuna melt that was not as tasty as the one from Red Velvet, but probably healthier. Since Jessica was too full for dessert, we took it to go. they had 2 kinds of GF vegan cupcakes, as well as 4 varieties of regular ones and this most delicious looking strawberry shortcake cupcake.</p>

<p><a href="http://ieatcupcakes.com/2012/03/11/cafe-flore-strawberry-shortcake-cupcake/strawberry-shortcake/" rel="attachment wp-att-1092"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-1092" title="strawberry-shortcake" src="http://ieatcupcakes.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/03/strawberry-shortcake-e1335846003693-382x510.jpg" alt="" width="382" height="510" /></a></p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Girl Scout Cupcakes? Can life get better?]]></title>
    <link href="http://purplicious.github.com/blog/2012/03/08/girl-scout-cupcakes-can-life-get-better/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-08T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://purplicious.github.com/blog/2012/03/08/girl-scout-cupcakes-can-life-get-better</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was pretty sure I had hit a high point in life a couple of years ago when Douglas&#8217; ex-co-worker made vegan samoas, and I got to have one for my very own. But I was wrong. I&#8217;m pretty sure this vegan cupcake version of a samoa wins by a long shot. I can&#8217;t wait to make them! But until then, I&#8217;ll be drooling over this picture of them.
<a href="http://ieatcupcakes.com/2012/03/08/girl-scout-cupcakes-can-life-get-better/samoacupcakes/" rel="attachment wp-att-1085"><img src="http://ieatcupcakes.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/03/samoacupcakes.jpg" alt="" title="samoacupcakes" width="491" height="368" class="alignleft size-full wp-image-1085" /></a>
The Recipe
http://goodveg.squidoo.com/recipes/desserts-recipes/beggin-for-samoa-cupcakes</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cupcake dollhousewarming]]></title>
    <link href="http://purplicious.github.com/blog/2012/03/06/cupcake-dollhousewarming/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-06T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://purplicious.github.com/blog/2012/03/06/cupcake-dollhousewarming</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Virginia had the most amazing idea of making cupcake (and other sweets, if you believe in those) hair accessories, and since I had just moved into my new dollhouse, we decided to make it a cupcake-themed dollhousewarming party. I know, I know, I should have thought of something more original&#8230;.if I have to go to another cupcake-themed dollhousewarming party, I will seriously rip my hair out. Well, mediocrity is just the theme of my life&#8230;if you don&#8217;t like it, don&#8217;t read about it.</p>

<p>In addition to making hair accessories, we also had the option of decorating cupcakes to match our hair creation. I&#8217;m not sure what happened to the rest of the photographs from this event. There may have been one of my first hair accessory, which was a 3D cupcake on a headband, but it was so ugly that I asked Zen to hide it forever, which ended up turning into a fun game of him laughing everytime he saw it, and me wishing I had burned it on a stake. Luckily, no photographic evidence remains of that failed attempt, and I still had plenty of time to make the smallish cupcake bow featured in this lovely photo taken by Josipa.</p>

<p><a href="http://ieatcupcakes.com/2012/03/06/cupcake-dollhousewarming/cupcake-bow/" rel="attachment wp-att-1080"><img src="http://ieatcupcakes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/12/cupcake-bow-436x510.jpg" alt="" title="cupcake-bow" width="436" height="510" class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-1080" /></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Back-to-school cupcakes]]></title>
    <link href="http://purplicious.github.com/blog/2011/09/10/back-to-school-cupcakes/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-10T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://purplicious.github.com/blog/2011/09/10/back-to-school-cupcakes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Apparently, cupcakes are the new apple because Isabelle insisted on bringing cupcakes to school on the first day of 4th grade. Kylene (former 2nd grade teacher) said that this tactic was a good one, because not only are cupcakes wayyyyy better than apples (those might not have been the exact words she used), but it would ensure that Isabelle will be well-liked by all the cupcake-eating nine-year-olds. I suggested the idea of making cupcake minis for numerous reasons including 1) the children are mini and therefore their cupcakes should match, 2) making 29 full-sized cupcakes means tripling the batch, which is just ridiculous, and 3) I figured for the teacher&#8217;s first day back after summer break, she might not appreciate having a class full of children drugged on high quantities of sugar.
So, Isabelle chose chocolate cupcakes with mint icing. Over the course of 2 nights, she made all the cupcakes herself and was ultra excited to use the piping bag to ice them for her very first time.
<a href="http://ieatcupcakes.com/2011/09/10/back-to-school-cupcakes/minis/" rel="attachment wp-att-1058"><img src="http://ieatcupcakes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/09/minis-510x345.jpg" alt="" title="minis" width="510" height="345" class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-1058" /></a></p>

<p><a href="http://ieatcupcakes.com/2011/09/10/back-to-school-cupcakes/isabelle-icing-cupcakes/" rel="attachment wp-att-1057"><img src="http://ieatcupcakes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/09/Isabelle-icing-cupcakes-510x505.jpg" alt="" title="Isabelle-icing-cupcakes" width="510" height="505" class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-1057" /></a></p>

<p><a href="http://ieatcupcakes.com/2011/09/10/back-to-school-cupcakes/icing-minis/" rel="attachment wp-att-1055"><img src="http://ieatcupcakes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/09/icing-minis-510x491.jpg" alt="" title="icing-minis" width="510" height="491" class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-1055" /></a></p>

<p><a href="http://ieatcupcakes.com/2011/09/10/back-to-school-cupcakes/icing-minis2/" rel="attachment wp-att-1056"><img src="http://ieatcupcakes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/09/icing-minis2-465x510.jpg" alt="" title="icing-minis2" width="465" height="510" class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-1056" /></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hello Kitty Cupcakes]]></title>
    <link href="http://purplicious.github.com/blog/2011/08/31/hello-kitty-cupcakes/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-31T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://purplicious.github.com/blog/2011/08/31/hello-kitty-cupcakes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In an effort to further draw out my birthday (regularly occurring annually in May) as noted in the blogpost about <a href="http://www.ieatcupcakes.com/2011/08/18/rilakkuma-cupcakes" target="_blank">Jessica&#8217;s birthday</a>, we had my final birthday celebration (shared with Lulu&#8217;s birthday&#8230;just one of the few caveats of making your birthday last 4 months) this past weekend under the guise of hello kitty karaoke!</p>

<p>Pandora karaoke may not have the best music selection, but what they lack in musical quality, they make up for in hot chicks that work there and an ultra-cute hello-kitty-themed private karaoke room. Oh, they also search your stuff on your way in so don&#8217;t try to be too sneaky (or at least not via purse).</p>

<p>In order to prepare for this momentous occasion, I hired cupcake <del datetime="2011-09-01T04:48:14+00:00">slaves</del> elves (correction by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/chocolatecupcakes/6095292413" target="_blank">Jocelyn</a>) to assist in the two-day process of making hello-kitty-themed cupcakes.</p>

<p>This music video is brought to you by the policy strictly adhered to by all EY employees that they refer to as the &#8220;picture or it didn&#8217;t happen&#8221; policy. In this case, the picture format requested was that of a music video, which Jessica flawlessly provided within moments of the request. I hope that all current and former EY employees request photographic evidence of all cupcake-making adventures forevermore, as it helps my blog become a more multi-dimensional archive of vegan cupcake insanity.</p>

<iframe width="460" height="345" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/gKH_oeH8CTw" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>Now that the documentation of cupcake creation has been covered, let&#8217;s watch the funnest (yes, <a href="http://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=funnest" target="_blank">funnest</a> is a word) part of cupcakes - the devouration! (yes, that&#8217;s a word too&#8230;no need to look it up&#8230;put the dictionary down right now! I have a spatula and I&#8217;m not afraid to use it.)</p>

<p>Eidelyn is my most talented photographing friend, so needless to say, the following photos are all hers!
<a href="http://http://www.flickr.com/photos/chocolatecupcakes/6102354944" rel="Hello Kitty cupcakes"><img src="http://ieatcupcakes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/cupcakes1-510x340.jpg" alt="Hello Kitty cupcakes" title="Hello Kitty cupcakes" width="510" height="340" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-1024" /></a></p>

<p>If I had a time machine*, I would go back and draw whiskers on Jessica and Virginia because seriously??!!! How effing adorable are they???? It&#8217;s actually probably best that they didn&#8217;t have whiskers or I might have mistaken them for cupcakes (and myself for a cat) and licked their cute little faces.</p>

<p><a href="http://http://www.flickr.com/photos/chocolatecupcakes/6102354198" rel="Jessica and Virginia"><img src="http://ieatcupcakes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/Jessica-Virginia-510x340.jpg" alt="Jessica and Virginia" title="Jessica and Virginia" width="510" height="340" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-1025" /></a></p>

<p>Pamela and I with the peeping hello kitty and of course, cupcakes!</p>

<p><a href="http://ieatcupcakes.com/?attachment_id=1035" rel="Pamela and Robin"><img src="http://ieatcupcakes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/cupcakes-Pam-me-510x510.jpg" alt="Pamela and Robin" title="Pamela and Robin" width="510" height="510" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-1035" /></a></p>

<p>This is what happens when you eat too many hello kitty cupcakes. You start turning into a kitty.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/chocolatecupcakes/6102393844" rel="Hello Kitty karaoke"><img src="http://ieatcupcakes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/groupshot-510x340.jpg" alt="Hello Kitty karaoke" title="Hello Kitty karaoke" width="510" height="340" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-1030" /></a></p>

<p>*I would also go back to that time I met that stupid mean boy in my 4th/5th grade combination class who wrote my phone number all over the entirety of Milpitas, causing what seemed like an eternity of prank calls to my house, and I&#8217;d have used better judgement in giving out my phone number. If anyone wants to hunt him down, and deliver a punishment, his name was Ed Fletcher. I will repay you in cupcakes&#8230;.the amount/flavor dependent on the severity of his lashings.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[PB&J cupcakes]]></title>
    <link href="http://purplicious.github.com/blog/2011/08/23/pbj-cupcakes/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://purplicious.github.com/blog/2011/08/23/pbj-cupcakes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>During the time Marcie worked with me, I never realized that an adult could eat so much peanut butter and jelly. She was more obsessed with these sandwiches than a child. I never understood the appeal really. I like my food savory and my sweets ultra-sweet. I&#8217;m not down with fruit in my salad or lightly sweetened desserts. So, while I was preparing for Marcie&#8217;s birthday celebration (aka. picking out bows), I was trying to figure out a way to make a peanut butter and jelly sound good to me. My conclusion was to take away the bread, add chocolate (there&#8217;s really no point in eating anything that doesn&#8217;t involve chocolate), and pump up the sweetness. Behold the Peanut Butter and Jelly chocolate cupcake! It&#8217;s basically just the <a href="http://ieatcupcakes.com/e-t-cupcake-recipe/">E.T. cupcake recipe</a>, but with strawberry preserves injected in the center. Jessica kindly recorded the injection process, but it was more out of disgust than awe. Regardless of her intentions, now there will be no question as to how to make these delicious cupcakes. Warning: If you are prone to motion sickness (or injection sickness), you may choose to skip this (not so) entertaining movie.</p>

<iframe width="420" height="345" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/UJ9aPV9JbEE" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>The icing didn&#8217;t come out as pretty as I had hoped because I decided to try to use mostly peanut butter and very little shortening or earth balance. Marcie is a personal trainer, so I knew she wouldn&#8217;t want a lot of fat in her birthday cupcakes. If you follow the recipe exactly, your icing with be much prettier.</p>

<p><a rel="attachment wp-att-983" href="http://ieatcupcakes.com/2011/08/23/pbj-cupcakes/img_3500/"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-983" title="PB&amp;J cupcakes" src="http://ieatcupcakes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/IMG_3500-382x510.jpg" alt="" width="382" height="510" /></a></p>

<p>Here&#8217;s the birthday girl with (what&#8217;s left of) her cupcakes.</p>

<p><a rel="attachment wp-att-986" href="http://ieatcupcakes.com/2011/08/23/pbj-cupcakes/img_1418/"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-986" title="Happy Birthday Marcie!" src="http://ieatcupcakes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/IMG_1418-510x382.jpg" alt="" width="510" height="382" /></a></p>

<p>Marcie with her friend with the well-manicured hands.</p>

<p><a rel="attachment wp-att-993" href="http://ieatcupcakes.com/2011/08/23/pbj-cupcakes/marcie-and-boy/"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-993" title="Enjoying the cupcake" src="http://ieatcupcakes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/marcie-and-boy-510x382.jpg" alt="" width="510" height="382" /></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rilakkuma Cupcakes]]></title>
    <link href="http://purplicious.github.com/blog/2011/08/18/rilakkuma-cupcakes/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-18T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://purplicious.github.com/blog/2011/08/18/rilakkuma-cupcakes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a rel="attachment wp-att-965" href="http://ieatcupcakes.com/2011/08/18/rilakkuma-cupcakes/rc/"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-965" title="Rilakkuma Cupcakes" src="http://ieatcupcakes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/rc-510x500.jpg" alt="" width="510" height="500" /></a>
Jessica (like myself) is pretty good at drawing out the whole birthday thing to get as much mileage out of it as possible. She&#8217;ll never be as good as I am at this, but she can always strive for my status.*  Being the good student that she is, Jessica had a super fun adventure on her birthday week that involved a scavenger hunt each day with fun games such as this one:
<a rel="attachment wp-att-960" href="http://ieatcupcakes.com/2011/08/18/rilakkuma-cupcakes/puzzle/"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-960" title="scavenger-hunt" src="http://ieatcupcakes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/puzzle-408x510.png" alt="" width="408" height="510" /></a></p>

<p>And on the final day, she received a super cute rilakkuma soap dispenser for all her hard work during her birthday week.</p>

<p>Then, true to the milking-a-birthday-for-all-it&#8217;s-worth mentality, she got to have a <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/chocolatecupcakes/sets/72157627425671870/with/6048653362/" target="_blank">birthday party</a> 2 weeks after her birthday! It was a super fun and crazy party, one in which I did not want to leave, but luckily, Lulu and Randy (thank you guys!) were ready to go at a reasonable hour so I was able to wake up in the morning and drag myself out of bed to take my mommy to brunch in SF. The best part of the entire party was when Jessica made the rule that all cupcakes had to be eaten in a lady-and-the-tramp-pasta-scene style. Oh, the fun! The best ones are <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/chocolatecupcakes/6039779820/in/set-72157627425671870">here</a> and <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/chocolatecupcakes/6048100777/in/set-72157627425671870">here</a>.</p>

<p>This post is all out of order. So, let&#8217;s get into a DeLorean and go back to the day of Jessica&#8217;s party when we were at Great America all day, and around 5 something I remembered that I was supposed to make cupcakes for her party! So, we raced home, and I baked the fastest batch of <a href="http://ieatcupcakes.com/e-t-cupcake-recipe/">peanut butter chocolate cupcakes</a> that I have ever baked in my life. I got home at 6:15pm and Lulu and Randy were coming at 7:30pm to pick me up. I still needed to shower and get ready for the party, make dinner for the family, eat (this is important because whenever I drink without eating dinner, bad bad things happen), and make and decorate the cupcakes. There was no way I would have gotten all of this done without my child-mom-slave labor camp I employ. Look at them hard at work!</p>

<p><a rel="attachment wp-att-970" href="http://ieatcupcakes.com/2011/08/18/rilakkuma-cupcakes/isabelle/"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-970" title="slave laborer #1" src="http://ieatcupcakes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/isabelle-382x510.jpg" alt="" width="382" height="510" /></a></p>

<p><a rel="attachment wp-att-971" href="http://ieatcupcakes.com/2011/08/18/rilakkuma-cupcakes/zen/"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-971" title="slave laborer #2" src="http://ieatcupcakes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/zen-382x510.jpg" alt="" width="382" height="510" /></a></p>

<p>Here is the final result after the attack:</p>

<p><a rel="attachment wp-att-972" href="http://ieatcupcakes.com/2011/08/18/rilakkuma-cupcakes/cupcakes-2/"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-972" title="cupcakes" src="http://ieatcupcakes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/cupcakes-510x382.jpg" alt="" width="510" height="382" /></a></p>

<ul>
<li>Proof #1: Me still <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/chocolatecupcakes/6048653362" target="_blank">receiving birthday presents</a> at Jessica&#8217;s birthday party (My birthday was May 21: over 2 months ago)</li>
<li>Proof #2: My Hello Kitty karaoke party is scheduled for next Friday night (almost 3 months past my actually birthday)</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[CupcakeCamp]]></title>
    <link href="http://purplicious.github.com/blog/2011/08/15/cupcakecamp/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://purplicious.github.com/blog/2011/08/15/cupcakecamp</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>David found this because it&#8217;s bears a resemblance to some nerdy-open-source-project-thingie that he&#8217;s always getting himself into. I don&#8217;t know much about it, except that it will be people eating cupcakes, which hopefully will include some baked (and eaten) by me (and hopefully you)!  If anyone is interested in going to this with me to sample cupcakes, or just baking/decorating with me, let me know because this sounds like it could potentially be awesome (as long as it has nothing to do with camping&#8230;or the outdoors&#8230;or bugs).</p>

<p><a href="http://cupcakecamp.org/" target="_blank">CupcakeCamp</a> will be held on Sunday, October 23rd, 2011 from 2-5pm (but really? will cupcakes last that long??? I think not!)</p>

<p><a rel="CupcakeCamp" href="http://cupcakecamp.org/" target="_blank"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-944" title="CupcakeCamp logo" src="http://ieatcupcakes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/Screen-shot-2011-08-15-at-11.03.01-PM.png" alt="" width="142" height="132" /></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tropical Cupcakes]]></title>
    <link href="http://purplicious.github.com/blog/2011/07/10/tropical-cupcakes/"/>
    <updated>2011-07-10T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://purplicious.github.com/blog/2011/07/10/tropical-cupcakes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div>Quantity: unknown. I have never in my life multiplied a recipe by 6 before, so I have absolutely no clue how many cupcakes this recipe should make, but lets just guess around 22.

Cake Ingredients
<ul>
    <li>2 c flour</li>
    <li>1 t baking soda</li>
    <li>1 t baking powder</li>
    <li>½ t salt</li>
    <li>2 c shredded coconut</li>
    <li>2/3 c coconut oil</li>
    <li>2 T lime zest</li>
    <li>1 ½ c sugar</li>
    <li>2 c coconut milk</li>
    <li>½ c soymilk</li>
    <li>1 T vanilla extract</li>
</ul>
Cake Directions

Melt oil over low heat on stove. Add sugar, milks, vanilla, and lime zest. Whisk to combine.

Sift together the first 4 dry ingredients in a large bowl. Add the coconut.

Add dry ingredients to wet, until incorporated.

Bake in a 350º oven for 24 minutes.

Icing Ingredients
<ul>
    <li>½ c margarine (earth balance)</li>
    <li>½ c palm shortening</li>
    <li>1 t vanilla</li>
    <li>1/4 cup lime juice</li>
    <li>4 c powdered sugar</li>
</ul>
Icing Directions

Beat together the margarine and palm shortening until fluffy.

Add the confectioner’s sugar, sifting it in, and then beat until smooth and fluffy (~3 minutes).

Add vanilla and lime juice and beat for 5-7 more minutes.

</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Renegade Craft Fair Summer 2011]]></title>
    <link href="http://purplicious.github.com/blog/2011/07/10/renegade-craft-fair-summer-2011/"/>
    <updated>2011-07-10T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://purplicious.github.com/blog/2011/07/10/renegade-craft-fair-summer-2011</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Every year at Renegade, we notice a particular theme that is popular at that time. We&#8217;ve seen owls, squirrels, and cupcakes. While we were walking the 3758 miles from our parking spot to Fort Mason, we were trying to make guesses on what would win the title of &#8220;most popular theme&#8221; this year. As it turned out, it was a tie. Although Eidelyn was convinced that Godzilla was sure to be the winner, he only appeared at one booth (that I noticed), while the main contestants for the prize were anchors, robots, and narwhales. Was there another one??? I can&#8217;t recall. By the end I could only focus on changing my shoes..haha. However, just when I thought I could focus on nothing other than my ouchy shoes, Zen so politely pointed out these cupcakes, which were the first and only cupcakes I had seen all day (which only served to enforce mine and Eidelyn&#8217;s theory that donuts are the new cupcake). Aren&#8217;t they adorbs? And the only thing cuter is that the maker of these babies goes by the name of <a href="http://www.etsy.com/shop/goodbyebluemonday?section_id=6627414">goodbyebluemonday</a>!!!</p>

<p><a rel="attachment wp-att-931" href="http://ieatcupcakes.com/2011/07/10/renegade-craft-fair-summer-2011/heartcupcake/"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-931" title="heartcupcake" src="http://ieatcupcakes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/07/heartcupcake-494x510.jpg" alt="" width="494" height="510" /></a></p>

<p><a rel="attachment wp-att-933" href="http://ieatcupcakes.com/2011/07/10/renegade-craft-fair-summer-2011/sprinkle-cupcake/"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-933" title="sprinkle cupcake" src="http://ieatcupcakes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/07/sprinkle-cupcake-429x510.jpg" alt="" width="429" height="510" /></a></p>

<p><a rel="attachment wp-att-932" href="http://ieatcupcakes.com/2011/07/10/renegade-craft-fair-summer-2011/img_1240/"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-932" title="IMG_1240" src="http://ieatcupcakes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/07/IMG_1240-510x382.jpg" alt="" width="510" height="382" /></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Carrot Cupcakes Recipe]]></title>
    <link href="http://purplicious.github.com/blog/2011/07/09/carrot-cupcakes-recipe/"/>
    <updated>2011-07-09T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://purplicious.github.com/blog/2011/07/09/carrot-cupcakes-recipe</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div>

Quantity: This recipe (VCTOTW) claims to make 24 cupcakes, but it actually makes only 16 if you fill them high enough to make them worth a damn. So, I need to tweak this recipe a bit (darn, more carrot cupcakes in my future). When I get it perfect, I&#8217;ll replace this recipe with a better one.

Cake Ingredients
<ul>
    <li>1½ c flour</li>
    <li>1½ baking soda</li>
    <li>1 t baking powder</li>
    <li>½ t salt</li>
    <li>½ t cinnamon</li>
    <li>1/4 t nutmeg</li>
    <li>1/4 t ginger</li>
    <li>1 1/3 c sugar</li>
    <li>8 oz vanilla wholesoy yogurt</li>
    <li>2/3 c sunflower oil</li>
    <li>1 T vanilla extract</li>
    <li>2 c grated carrots (The recipe called for 1 cup, but my mommy always taught me when making carrot cake to double the amount of carrots it calls for because it makes them moister and healthier)</li>
    <li>1 c walnuts</li>
</ul>
Cake Directions

Sift together the first 7 dry ingredients in a large bowl.

In a mixing bowl, mix together sugar, oil, yogurt, and vanilla.

Add the dry ingredients to the wet slowly, and mix.

Add grated carrots and mix until evenly coated. Add walnuts.

Bake in a 350º oven for 24 minutes.

Icing Ingredients
<ul>
    <li>½ c margarine</li>
    <li>½ c tofutti</li>
    <li>2 t vanilla</li>
    <li>4 c powdered sugar</li>
</ul>
Icing Directions

Beat together the margarine, cream cheese, and vanilla extract.

Add the confectioner’s sugar, sifting it in, and then beat until smooth and fluffy.

</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Carrot Cake Cupcakes!]]></title>
    <link href="http://purplicious.github.com/blog/2011/07/08/carrot-cake-cupcakes/"/>
    <updated>2011-07-08T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://purplicious.github.com/blog/2011/07/08/carrot-cake-cupcakes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Why have I never thought to make <a href="http://ieatcupcakes.com/carrot-cupcakes-recipe/">carrot cake cupcakes</a> before? Did I forget how delicious carrot cake was? Is it the lack of chocolatey goodness in them that my aversion, forgetfulness, or avoidance stems from? I don&#8217;t think anyone really knows the answer to these questions, however, I must say that carrot cake cupcakes might just be the new chocolate cupcake for me. I made these for the first time in celebration of Eidelyn&#8217;s birthday. The craft girls all nominated me to be the delivery girl; not because I look like kiki the delivery witch (although I did after my stylist freshly dyed my hair black the weekend before), but because I work in Palo Alto, the closest to Redwood City (workplace of the birthday girl).</p>

<p>Because I have no need to make test tube babies (Who in their right mind would have children on purpose?!), I hadn&#8217;t actually ever been to Eidelyn&#8217;s place of employment before this delivery day. So, when I arrived at what google maps (a.k.a. lying-ass-maps) told me was the correct location, I parked and got out with cupcakes and homemade cards in hand, ready to kiki it up. This is where my day started going a little haywire. So, because Eidelyn is a fancy sort of girl, I had dressed up that day and even worn heels! I know, I know, the real kiki didn&#8217;t wear heels, but I&#8217;m like the grown up version of kiki, who traded in her shoes and broom for heels and a <span style="text-decoration: line-through;">unicorn</span> Prius. So, here&#8217;s the funny part. Eidelyn&#8217;s work wasn&#8217;t actually on middlefield road, like the address suggests. So, I walked (in heels, don&#8217;t forget) over these rocky train tracks and through an enormous parking lot in search of her work. Once I finally found it, probably with sweat sticking my baby hairs to my forehead in an oh-so-attractive-and-negating-the-point-of-dressing-nice kind of way, I knocked on the door and was greeted by some very helpful co-workers who informed me that Eidelyn wasn&#8217;t at work that day due to Jury Duty!!!!</p>

<p>Sooooo&#8230;.because I traded in my broom, I was forced to walk all the way back to my car, still carrying birthday treats, and waded through the rocky highlands (train tracks) yet again. Long story short, by the time I finally reached Eidelyn&#8217;s house and banged the door knocker against the house numerous times, I was so exhausted that I had to leave only 11 cupcakes on her porch, because without the sustenance provided by that twelfth cupcake, I may have never made it back to work.</p>

<p>It was all worth it though when she found <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/soundinwater/5889102542">her treats</a> and sent me the best string of emojis that ever existed.</p>

<p><a rel="attachment wp-att-908" href="http://ieatcupcakes.com/2011/07/08/carrot-cake-cupcakes/ccc/"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-908" title="ccc" src="http://ieatcupcakes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/07/ccc-382x510.jpg" alt="" width="382" height="510" /></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vegan cupcakes in Vancouver]]></title>
    <link href="http://purplicious.github.com/blog/2011/07/03/vegan-cupcakes-in-vancouver/"/>
    <updated>2011-07-03T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://purplicious.github.com/blog/2011/07/03/vegan-cupcakes-in-vancouver</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>First spotting of a vegan cupcake since arriving in Vancouver. Karmavore also had vegan soft serve, gardein burgers, and nachos with teese nacho cheesesauce.</p>

<p><a href="http://ieatcupcakes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/07/l_2048_1536_F7D7B399-77D8-4AB8-84A9-CE97537EE97F.jpeg"><img src="http://ieatcupcakes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/07/l_2048_1536_F7D7B399-77D8-4AB8-84A9-CE97537EE97F.jpeg" alt="" width="300" height="225" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-364" /></a></p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Death by Chocolate]]></title>
    <link href="http://purplicious.github.com/blog/2011/07/03/death-by-chocolate/"/>
    <updated>2011-07-03T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://purplicious.github.com/blog/2011/07/03/death-by-chocolate</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When I first read the &#8220;closed&#8221; sign at Edible Flours after taking a bus for the sole purpose of trying the vegan truffles and stuffed cupcakes, my first reaction was sadness and my second inclination was to vandalize the exterior of their business. How could they be closed after I traveled by plane from California for their cupcakes? It brought back memories of that time that Jocelyn and I walked forever in Portland for vegan soft serve (on this very weekend 2 years ago), only to end in me staring through glass to a desolate let-down. After the disappointment waned, and I hopped on a bus back to gastown, I hopped off the bus to transfer and low and behold, I was in front of a place called death by chocolate! What better way to die???? There isn&#8217;t one&#8230;trust me. I was preparing myself for the disappointment of there being nothing vegan for me, when my spirits were pleasantly lifted! Vegan chocolate cupcakes!!!!</p>

<p><a rel="Death by Chocolate" href="http://ieatcupcakes.com/2011/07/03/death-by-chocolate/death-by-chocolate-2/"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-896" title="death-by-chocolate" src="http://ieatcupcakes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/07/death-by-chocolate-510x382.jpg" alt="" width="510" height="382" /></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fox & Fawn, how cute are you?]]></title>
    <link href="http://purplicious.github.com/blog/2011/06/29/fox-fawn-how-cute-are-you/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-29T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://purplicious.github.com/blog/2011/06/29/fox-fawn-how-cute-are-you</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This vegan bakery is apparently located nearby in the vicinity of the northeast bay area and their <a href="http://foxandfawn.com/home.html" target="_blank">website</a> makes me want to redesign mine asap. Jessica and Josipa, can we go back to having dev night once a week? Pleeease! If <a href="http://foxandfawn.com/home.html" target="_blank">this</a> isn&#8217;t inspiration, I don&#8217;t know what can be. Except maybe <a href="http://ipap.me/" target="_blank">this</a>. Because honestly, who doesn&#8217;t love the idea of getting their annual pap smear through the internet.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jelly Belly cupcake decorating contest]]></title>
    <link href="http://purplicious.github.com/blog/2011/06/13/jelly-belly-cupcake-decorating-contest/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://purplicious.github.com/blog/2011/06/13/jelly-belly-cupcake-decorating-contest</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I <em>was</em> excited about this contest when Jocelyn first told me about it because I <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/chocolatecupcakes/4863362891/" target="_blank">already</a> often decorate cupcakes with jelly bellys since they&#8217;re actually a vegan decoration that is easy to acquire, but after seeing some of the cupcakes other people have made, intimidation has set in 150%.</p>

<p><a rel="attachment wp-att-879" href="http://ieatcupcakes.com/2011/06/13/jelly-belly-cupcake-decorating-contest/screen-shot-2011-06-13-at-9-48-37-pm/"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-879" title="jelly belly contest" src="http://ieatcupcakes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/Screen-shot-2011-06-13-at-9.48.37-PM-463x510.png" alt="" width="463" height="510" /></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vegan Bakesale this Saturday]]></title>
    <link href="http://purplicious.github.com/blog/2011/06/12/vegan-bakesale-this-saturday/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-12T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://purplicious.github.com/blog/2011/06/12/vegan-bakesale-this-saturday</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a rel="attachment wp-att-873" href="http://ieatcupcakes.com/2011/06/12/vegan-bakesale-this-saturday/sfveganbakesalejune2011/"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-873" title="sfveganbakesaleJune2011" src="http://ieatcupcakes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/sfveganbakesaleJune2011.jpg" alt="" width="398" height="612" /></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vegan cupcakes at SFO]]></title>
    <link href="http://purplicious.github.com/blog/2011/05/28/vegan-cupcakes-at-sfo/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-28T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://purplicious.github.com/blog/2011/05/28/vegan-cupcakes-at-sfo</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>when I first heard that virgin airlines changed to a different terminal, I wasn&#8217;t excited due to my resistance to change. However, now that I&#8217;m living the good life in terminal 2, I&#8217;m instantly warmed to the change. the food court has a plant cafe with vegan banana bread and 2 kinds of vegan cupcakes!!!!</p>

<p><a href="http://ieatcupcakes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/l_2048_1536_7F6C098C-C450-4725-BE28-ADA485CF80EE.jpeg"><img src="http://ieatcupcakes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/l_2048_1536_7F6C098C-C450-4725-BE28-ADA485CF80EE.jpeg" alt="" width="300" height="225" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-364" /></a></p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
